<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SGVLUG]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-27T16:19:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/10/11/strace/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/10/11/strace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting&#8230;<br/>
using the tool we all love to hate.</p>

<p>The Presentation will cover the Linux command line utility &#8216;strace&#8217; and some of it&#8217;s many uses.  It will cover the basics of Linux System Calls and their use.  The presentation will use examples throughout to provide genuine use-cases for the tool.  The Presentation is focused on Practical Application Troubleshooting, it will not be an in-depth guide to the various System Calls.  I will demonstrate many techniques that can help you to gain a deeper understanding of application execution flow on a Linux system.</p>

<p>Speaker: David Rodriguez  &#8211;  otherwise known as&#8230; ‘D Rod’ <br/>
  Currently working as Linux Systems Engineer &#8211; managing various types of Linux servers (Web App, DB, Chef, Nagios, etc.)<br/>
  3+ years as a Linux Systems Engineer<br/>
  5+ years as a Windows Systems Engineer<br/>
  10+ years as a Linux User<br/>
  B.S. in Information Systems Security &amp; A.S. in Computer and Electronic Engineering<br/>
  Strong Advocate for Open Source<br/>
  I like to break web applications&#8230;   :-)</p>

<p>Date: Thursday, October 11, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SGVHAK SIG Kickoff]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/20/raspberry-pi-etc-sig/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/20/raspberry-pi-etc-sig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If you are interested in the group, please sign up for the [SGVHAK mailing list] (http://sgvlug.org/mailman/listinfo/hak &#8220;SGVHAK Mailing List Sign Up&#8221;).  We will continue to crosspost announcements to the SGVLUG mailing list. We are in the process of setting up a website or subpage.</em></p>

<p>Do you like working on hardware projects?  Did you just get a Raspberry Pi/Arduino/Kinect with the intentions of doing something cool?  Did you wish that there was a local meetup group where you can meet up with like-minded folks and actually make progress with your projects?</p>

<p>Come to our kickoff meeting on Thursday to discuss starting up this special interest group.  Connect with your fellow hardware geeks and share some of the projects you&#8217;ve been working on. And if we can decide on a name for the SIG, we can set up things like a mailing list, website, and wiki.</p>

<p>We have been kindly granted access to a room at Caltech for this meeting only.  It is a small classroom with about 30 student desks and a teacher desk.  We will have access to a projector and power.  There is an open wireless network.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday, September 20, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 119 (around the corner from usual LUG meeting room)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloning SysAdmins with the Cloud and Juju]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/13/cloning_sysadmins_with_the_cloud_and_juju/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/13/cloning_sysadmins_with_the_cloud_and_juju</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its time to face the music: There&#8217;s only a couple guys in Ops, and a
lot of infrastructure to set up and it was all due yesterday. If only
you could clone all the sysadmins of the world to get all of their
expertise and know-how in deploying open source applications, you could
actually get it done. Perhaps there is a way: Juju and Charms! Juju
encapsulates services in a way that promotes sharing and collaboration
the same way packages have done for open source software.  If you are
a sysadmin or a developer who is looking to get an infrastructure of
databases, loadbalancers, and webapps up to speed rapidly, Juju may
be interesting. If you are looking into deploying something massively
scalable, like OpenStack or Hadoop, Juju is built to handle that task.</p>

<p>Speaker: Clint Byrum is a member of the Canonical Ubuntu Server Team, bringing
years of Ops and Development experience in web environments to the task
of making Ubuntu Server shine. <br/>
Date: Thursday, September 13, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinect Programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/08/09/kinect-programming/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/08/09/kinect-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Doug Vargas will talk about programming for the Kinect motion sensing input device by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Speaker: Doug Vargas <br/>
Date: Thursday, August 9, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Discussion]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/07/12/open-discussion/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/07/12/open-discussion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No scheduled speaker. Open discussion continued afterwards at Burger Continental.</p>

<p>We will have a brief overview of <a href="http://git-scm.com">Git</a>.</p>

<p>Speaker: You! <br/>
Date: Thursday, July 12, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build your own cloud hosted social network with Ruby on Rails, Git and Heroku]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/06/14/cloud-hosted-social-network/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/06/14/cloud-hosted-social-network</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ruby on Rails is an open source framework for developing database driven websites.  Git is a source control management tool.  Heroku is web hosting in the cloud.  In this talk Homan Chou and David Ferril will give a brief overview of each of these tools and give a case study of a real
working social network.</p>

<p>Speaker: Homan Chou and David Ferril <br/>
Date: Thursday, June 14, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rasberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/05/10/may-2012-raspberry-pi/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/05/10/may-2012-raspberry-pi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Raspberry Pi is a $35, 256MB educational computer that runs Linux.
Dan Kegel will demonstrate how the Pi can be used as a
simple sensor network node, reporting observed Bluetooth
addresses to a central server, running on 4 AA batteries.</p>

<p>Speaker: Dan Kegel <br/>
Date: Thursday, May 10, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python Web Frameworks - Django and Pylons]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/04/12/april-2012-python-web-frameworks-django-and-pylons/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/04/12/april-2012-python-web-frameworks-django-and-pylons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The two dominant python-based web frameworks are Django and Pylons. They can be used to deploy web applications such as news sites, online ticket tracking systems, or wikis. An overview and comparison of Django and the recently reinvented Pylons Project will be presented. Individual dependencies of the Pylons Project will be described including the Pyramid WSGI engine, the SQLAlchemy database Object Relational Mapper (ORM), and the Mako HTML template generator. A very simple blog engine will be implemented as an instructive example.</p>

<p>Speaker: Braddock Gaskill (braddock .at. braddock.com) <br/>
Date: Thursday, April 12, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2012 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/03/08/march-2012-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/03/08/march-2012-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unity is the new desktop environment for Ubuntu, having first premiered in   <br/>
version 11.04, significantly enhanced with version 11.10, and very much the  <br/>
cornerstone of the upcoming 12.04 release.</p>

<p>A striking departure from Gnome 2, Unity has been seen as a source of        <br/>
controversy in the Linux world.</p>

<p>This talk will outline some of the design goals that Unity addresses, noting <br/>
strengths, weaknesses, and improvements across the three versions of Ubuntu in
which it&#8217;s been included.</p>

<p>While Unity offers many usability affordances, some Ubuntu users prefer to   <br/>
customize it for their specific workflows. Linux is famous for its           <br/>
customizability, and Unity is no exception if you know which tools to look   <br/>
for.</p>

<p>This presentation will outline some of the tools available through the Ubuntu<br/>
Software Center to show you how to customize the Unity interface.</p>

<p>Speaker Bio: Richard Gaskin is President of Fourth World, a software design  <br/>
and development consultancy in Los Angeles. Since founding the company in    <br/>
1994, he&#8217;s developed dozens of commercial and open source applications used by
a wide range of organizations, including FedEx, AOL, the US Library of       <br/>
Congress, and hundreds of universities around the world.</p>

<p>Although he started his career with Mac OS, Richard has since delivered      <br/>
applications for Irix, every version of Windows, and has been developing for <br/>
Linux for the last two years.</p>

<p>Richard has spoken at more than a dozen tech conferences, including UbuCon,  <br/>
LiveCode Developer Conference, and MacTech where he had the distinction of   <br/>
being the only presenter using Linux.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday March 8, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2012 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/02/09/february-2012-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/02/09/february-2012-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matt Cambell and Miguel Hernandez will talk about Drupal and their experiences
with using it to revamp the SGVLUG website.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday February 9, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[January 2012 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/01/12/january-2012-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/01/12/january-2012-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Topic: Horror Stories and Trouble shooting!</p>

<p>The idea is to have a fun meeting with some scary stories and trouble shooting
lessons to be learned. Depending on how quickly the presentation goes we may <br/>
have time to share more, so please feel free to bring your horror story and  <br/>
what you did to resolve it.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday January 12, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[December 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/12/08/december-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/12/08/december-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Topic: Virtual Private Servers: On a Budget</p>

<p>Christefano who was going to present Redmine is unavailable so we will try to<br/>
reschedule.</p>

<p>Virtual Private Servers: On a Budget - We will discuss a class of virtual    <br/>
private servers available at a low price point allowing individuals to get   <br/>
many of the benefits of dedicated hardware without the cost thanks to        <br/>
virtualization technologies and a competitive marketplace.</p>

<p>James McDuffie has worked for JPL for over 10 years and has been using Linux <br/>
since at least kernel version 1.3.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday December 8, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[November 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/11/10/november-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/11/10/november-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Topic: VPN: Keep the Spies away!</p>

<p>PPTP (with a demo on DDWRT) along with OpenVPN, L2TP, and IPsec Presenter: Dan
Buthusiem</p>

<p>Date: Thursday November 10, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/10/13/october-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/10/13/october-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SGVLUG meeting 9/8 7-9pm</p>

<p>Command Line &#8220;Tips and Tricks&#8221;</p>

<p>Lan Dang spends the majority of her working hours monitoring and             <br/>
troubleshooting data processing systems on Linux-based computer clusters. She<br/>
has accumulated a number of tips and tricks to deal with the command line. Her
arsenal includes: GNU screen, awk, sed, shell scripting, remote ssh command  <br/>
execution, bash command history, and a variety of system utilities. This talk<br/>
will cover useful one-liners and the small set of useful commands that will  <br/>
get you started using these tools or using them in new ways. Whether you&#8217;re a<br/>
newbie or a command line guru, you&#8217;ll probably pick up something useful for  <br/>
the next time you&#8217;re at the command line.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday October 13, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/09/08/september-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/09/08/september-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SGVLUG meeting 9/8 7-9pm</p>

<p>Topic: Disaster Recovery and Backups in the era of the cloud Presentation and<br/>
Discussion</p>

<p>Please bring your questions, opinions, and solutions for discussion!</p>

<p>Date: Thursday September 8, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/08/11/august-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/08/11/august-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monthly Meeting.</p>

<h2>Topic: Virtualmin / Webmin + Brief review Defcon/Blackhat:                     </h2>

<p>Take your Drupal sites to the next level with the free, open-source Webmin   <br/>
control panel and its powerful Virtualmin plug-in. Add as many features as you
want, including unlimited domains, mail accounts, Subversion repositories,   <br/>
mailing lists, and more with a point-and-click web interface.</p>

<p>Webmin and Virtualmin are similar to cPanel and WHM, respectively, and can   <br/>
manage dozens or even hundreds of domains. They are the perfect tools for    <br/>
creating test and development sites, hosting client websites or even managing<br/>
a full-blown online infrastructure for running a business.</p>

<p>Did we forget to mention, Webmin and Virtualmin are free* and open-source?   <br/>
Compared to site licensing costs of cPanel, WHM, Plesk and other proprietary <br/>
control panels, Webmin and Virtualmin cost only as much as a basic           <br/>
$10-20/month VPS account.</p>

<p>Bio: &#8212;&#8211; Christefano is CEO and Co-founder of Exaltation of Larks, where   <br/>
Virtualmin has been a key ingredient for rapid website deployment. He is a   <br/>
sysadmin for LA Drupal and the DrupalCamp LA website (which uses Virtualmin) <br/>
and has been on the Drupal.org and groups.drupal.org webmaster teams since   <br/>
2008. Exaltation of Larks, which provides Drupal consulting, development and <br/>
training http://www.larks.la</p>

<p>Date: Thursday August 11, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/07/14/july-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/07/14/july-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monthly meeting.</p>

<p>APRS is a amateur radio network where small packets of data such as position <br/>
reports, messages or telemetry are transmitted to other radio operators and  <br/>
eventually propagated to the Internet.                                       <br/>
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_Packet_Reporting_System</p>

<p>The proliferation of small, low power and easily hackable ARM devices opens up
many possibilities for setting up unobtrusive computing solutions. Amateur   <br/>
radio operator and long time Linux user James McDuffie (K6JLM) explores using<br/>
the Seagate GoFlex Net along with surplus amateur radio equipment to build a <br/>
APRS digipeater for helping to relay packets both over RF and to the Internet.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday July 14, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 <br/>
Location: 107 Downs Lab</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[June 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/06/09/june-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/06/09/june-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Caltech team participating in the U.S. Department of Energy 2011 Solar   <br/>
Decathlon will present their project, for which they are using various       <br/>
open-source technology.</p>

<p>&#8220;The Solar Decathlon is a U.S. Department of Energy Sponsored competition    <br/>
which challenges teams of college and graduate students from around the world<br/>
to design and build solar-powered, net-zero houses. Inside the SCI-Arc/Caltech
entry, code named CHIP, a sophisticated home automation system monitors every<br/>
watt of electricity consumed and visually communicates the information to    <br/>
homeowners. It also plays a central role in optimizing the behavior of the   <br/>
house at all times, such as by controlling operation of the active thermal   <br/>
mass, shutting down appliances or lights that are no longer used, and of     <br/>
course giving the homeowners an instant understanding into how their own     <br/>
behaviors affects their energy use and in turn their energy bill.&#8221;</p>

<p>http://chip2011.com/</p>

<p>Date: Thursday June 9, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  <br/>
Location: 107 Downs Lab</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/05/12/may-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/05/12/may-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monthly Meeting.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday May 12, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  <br/>
Location: Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[April 2011 Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/04/14/april-2011-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2011/04/14/april-2011-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Topic: Todd CC will discuss the impact of a world with rapidly changing      <br/>
technologies, radical fluctuations in staffing needs, and changes in the     <br/>
employer/employee dynamic and how you can be best prepared for your next job <br/>
and/or career. During this presentation, the relatively new catchphrase      <br/>
&#8220;DevOps&#8221; will be discussed as it pertains to job advancement and career      <br/>
opportunities.</p>

<p>Presenter: Cranston-Cuebas, Todd With 13 years of experience in technology   <br/>
staffing in Los Angeles, Todd has been through the dot-com boom and bust, the<br/>
housing boom and subsequent recession, and through it all, has kept a close  <br/>
eye on employment trends in technology.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday April 14, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                <br/>
Location: 107 Downs Lab</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
