<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meetings | SGVLUG]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/categories/meetings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T07:48:10-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/10/11/strace/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/10/11/strace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting...<br/>
using the tool we all love to hate.</p>

<p>The Presentation will cover the Linux command line utility 'strace' and some of it's many uses.  It will cover the basics of Linux System Calls and their use.  The presentation will use examples throughout to provide genuine use-cases for the tool.  The Presentation is focused on Practical Application Troubleshooting, it will not be an in-depth guide to the various System Calls.  I will demonstrate many techniques that can help you to gain a deeper understanding of application execution flow on a Linux system.</p>

<p>Speaker: David Rodriguez  --  otherwise known as... ‘D Rod’ <br/>
  Currently working as Linux Systems Engineer -- managing various types of Linux servers (Web App, DB, Chef, Nagios, etc.)<br/>
  3+ years as a Linux Systems Engineer<br/>
  5+ years as a Windows Systems Engineer<br/>
  10+ years as a Linux User<br/>
  B.S. in Information Systems Security &amp; A.S. in Computer and Electronic Engineering<br/>
  Strong Advocate for Open Source<br/>
  I like to break web applications...   :-)</p>

<p>Date: Thursday, October 11, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SGVHAK SIG Kickoff]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/20/raspberry-pi-etc-sig/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/20/raspberry-pi-etc-sig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If you are interested in the group, please sign up for the [SGVHAK mailing list] (http://sgvlug.org/mailman/listinfo/hak "SGVHAK Mailing List Sign Up").  We will continue to crosspost announcements to the SGVLUG mailing list. We are in the process of setting up a website or subpage.</em></p>

<p>Do you like working on hardware projects?  Did you just get a Raspberry Pi/Arduino/Kinect with the intentions of doing something cool?  Did you wish that there was a local meetup group where you can meet up with like-minded folks and actually make progress with your projects?</p>

<p>Come to our kickoff meeting on Thursday to discuss starting up this special interest group.  Connect with your fellow hardware geeks and share some of the projects you've been working on. And if we can decide on a name for the SIG, we can set up things like a mailing list, website, and wiki.</p>

<p>We have been kindly granted access to a room at Caltech for this meeting only.  It is a small classroom with about 30 student desks and a teacher desk.  We will have access to a projector and power.  There is an open wireless network.</p>

<p>Date: Thursday, September 20, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 119 (around the corner from usual LUG meeting room)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloning SysAdmins with the Cloud and Juju]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/13/cloning_sysadmins_with_the_cloud_and_juju/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/09/13/cloning_sysadmins_with_the_cloud_and_juju</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its time to face the music: There's only a couple guys in Ops, and a
lot of infrastructure to set up and it was all due yesterday. If only
you could clone all the sysadmins of the world to get all of their
expertise and know-how in deploying open source applications, you could
actually get it done. Perhaps there is a way: Juju and Charms! Juju
encapsulates services in a way that promotes sharing and collaboration
the same way packages have done for open source software.  If you are
a sysadmin or a developer who is looking to get an infrastructure of
databases, loadbalancers, and webapps up to speed rapidly, Juju may
be interesting. If you are looking into deploying something massively
scalable, like OpenStack or Hadoop, Juju is built to handle that task.</p>

<p>Speaker: Clint Byrum is a member of the Canonical Ubuntu Server Team, bringing
years of Ops and Development experience in web environments to the task
of making Ubuntu Server shine. <br/>
Date: Thursday, September 13, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinect Programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/08/09/kinect-programming/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/08/09/kinect-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Doug Vargas will talk about programming for the Kinect motion sensing input device by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Speaker: Doug Vargas <br/>
Date: Thursday, August 9, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Discussion]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/07/12/open-discussion/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sgvlug.org/blog/2012/07/12/open-discussion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No scheduled speaker. Open discussion continued afterwards at Burger Continental.</p>

<p>We will have a brief overview of <a href="http://git-scm.com">Git</a>.</p>

<p>Speaker: You! <br/>
Date: Thursday, July 12, 2012 @ 7 pm <br/>
Location: Caltech - Downs 107</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
